Jan Klug

Polymath Product Manager of 5 years, before that: UX, programming and investment banking (5 years funding and scaling startups). I've driven design, technology and business on a range of great products; equally happy during customer visits, code reviews and C-suite meetings. 3rd culture kid, working on my 7th language. Postgrad Computer Science, undergrad Philosophy Politics & Economics.

SKILLS, TOOLING & TECHNOLOGIES

Skills: A/B Testing, Agile Product Management, Business Development, Data-Driven Decision Making, Financial Modelling, Information Architecture, Offshoring, Machine Learning, Project Management, Roadmap Prioritization and Execution, Software Engineering, Strategic Planning, Technical Specification, UX Research, UI Design Tooling: Apple Testflight, Autodesk Sketchbook, Azure DevOPs (VSTS), Google Analytics, Google Firebase, Google Play Console, InVision, Jira, Lucidchart, Microsoft Office Suite, Power BI, SQL, Trello, Zendesk Technologies: AngularJS, C#, CSS, HTML, Ionic, Java, .Net Core, Node.js, Python, Unity, Vue.js

EXPERIENCE

Portfolio Product Manager - Ticketer | November 2017 - August 2020 | Transit Apps, Hardware and SaaS

Led cross-functional teams building products that power 80% of UK regional bus travel and move 2bn people per year, including: real-time financial and operational SaaS, passenger-facing mobile apps and webapps, on-bus ticketing/payments devices and commercial APIs.

- Led new products through full lifecycle, including iOS and Android apps. Worked hands-on with UX and Technical leads to design and architect, managed build by two offshore teams. Reprioritized roadmap based on customer feedback and analytics to ship key features 6 weeks early. For the first time ever, passengers can buy and share tickets from 30% (and growing) of the bus industry in one app
- **Discovered and evangelized** new products to fit **customer problems, research and strategic context**, e.g. APIs for real-time travel apps (**upsell to 50**% of customers) and demand-responsive transport (**4 ongoing pilots**)
- Prioritized and executed highest impact features on core products, such as contactless transit boarding, resulting in up to 80% conversion away from cash in some customers
- Proved that a viable data analytics product platform could be built at 20% of the cost by simplifying the problem and focusing on key use cases
- Ran customer requirement gathering sessions, established highest ROI enhancements to existing products, enabling us to sign our 2 largest customers, scaling revenue by 45%. Developed features into standalone products, such as digital safety checks, increasing recurring revenue by 7%.
- Managed partner integrations and long-term relationships with Apple (enabling Express Transit on most UK buses), Google (confidential) and Sapphire (integrating with EAM fleet management solution)
- Consulted Department for Transport's Bus Open Data Service as an industry expert, prevented architecture and regulation that would have been cost-prohibitive for 60% of industry. Also designed pro-bono COVID-19 travel monitoring for DfT
- As 1st Product Manger hire, implemented and continously improved best industry practices like Behavior-Driven-Design. Built collaborative team environment in partnership with UX, engineering and QA letting us move fast while reducing rework by 80% by anticipating challenges
- Established scalable A/B testing across 500 live SaaS portals and 25,000 in-field devices
- Proved value of the product function, trained 3 junior PMs to scale product team

Product Manager - Go4Venture | July 2015 - November 2017 | Financial Industry SaaS

Managed spin-out of startup financing marketplace from UK's leading tech-sector investment bank, Silverpeak.

- Used modern tooling and **in-house SQL database** to establish tech-enabled investment banking practice, enabling team to efficiently **manage 2x as many financing projects**
- Established bug tracking, analytics and oversaw backend migration of legacy product
- Translated learnings from investment banking into automated matchmaking and fundraising web platform.
- Designed MVP and personally coded prototype in AngularJS for user testing, signed 15 trial investors

Corporate Finance Analyst - Silverpeak Technology Investment Banking | July 2012 - July 2015 | Startup M&A

Raised capital for startup and scale-up companies. Advised on finance, strategy and product from pre-raise through to funding completion, and facilitated M&A exit to strategic and financial acquirers.

- Advised and facilitated £100m of startup funding and M&A
- Provided startup portfolio analysis consultancy and organised pitch days for Portugal Ventures
- Selected M&A targets and benchmarked industry for an undisclosed FTSE-100 software provider
- Researched, edited and published monthly tech sector fundraising coverage read by 5,000 subscribers
- Self-taught programming to automate job tasks, resigned to study MSc Computer Science at UCL

Corporate Finance Analyst Long Term Intern - Rothschild | February 2012 - July 2012 | Investment Banking (For details and experience pre-2012 see <u>LinkedIn</u>)

KEY PROJECTS

(For full portfolio see jan-made.com)

- ISSRAN | 2020: Personally developed gamified spaced repetition app helping users to entrain learning immersion by constructively using dead time to scroll infinite feed of flashcards
- Passwordless-SQLITE | 2017: Personally developed open-source node.js package enabling Passwordless to use sqlite as a token store for magic-link authentication
- Microsoft Cities Unlocked | 2016: Client liaison with Microsoft UK head of project UX, shipped cross-platform C# Unity app and .NET API. Later productionised as Microsoft Soundscape enabling visually impaired users to navigate urban environments.

EDUCATION

MSc Computer Science 1st Class Honours with Distinction - University College London | 2016. Focus: UX, Software Engineering, Cross-Platform Development

BA Philosophy Politics & Economics Upper 2nd Class Honours - Durham University | 2010. Focus: Econometrics, Philosophy of Logic

PERSONAL

Languages: Fluent English, Advanced German & Mandarin, Intermediate French & Cantonese, Basic Japanese & Italian

Nationalities: German Citizenship, Hong Kong Citizenship, China Residency, UK Residency

Interests: Carpentry, Cooking, Eastern Philosophy, Experimental Archaeology, Filmmaking, Foraging, History of Technology and Physical Culture, Jiu Jitsu, Pen & Paper Role Playing Games, Powerlifting